RYAN GROFSCH

Software Development Engineer | Seattle, WA | (206) 295-1320 | ryan.groesch@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/ryan-groesch github.com/ryan-g13 | http://ryang-portfolio.herokuapp.com/

Summary

Full-stack JavaScript Developer with 2 years of experience as a Software Development Engineer working in an Agile environment.

Technical Skills

Languages: JavaScript, TypeScript, Java, SQL/MySQL/PostgreSQL, HTML5, CSS3

Tools: React.js, Redux.js, Node.js, Express.js, JQuery, MongoDB, Jest, Artillery.io, Selenium, AWS, Github, Heroku, Angular 6/8 Methodologies: Agile, Scrum, Jira, TDD, SASS, SMACCSS, RESTful APIs, SDLC, OOP, Microservices, Services Oriented Architecture Operating Systems: OS X, Windows, Linux

Experience

T- Mobile | Software Development Engineer | Feb 2019 - Present

- · Currently building a Migration As Port Application using Typescript/Angular8/MaterialUI, and Java API layer
- Built a tool scaled for all T-Mobile customers, using Typescript/Angular6/MaterialUI with Karma and Jasmine for testing on the front end, Java Spring Boot for middleware/microservices with a MySql DB.
- Built internally consumed Hierarchy Tool, based on AWS Server-less architecture, and used by 25,000 T-Mobile employees using React Native/Redux with Typescript, Java Middleware / Lambda functions and a PostgreSQL DB.
- · Testing suite includes integration testing via Selenium and Jest/Enzyme/React-test-utils for front end mocking/unit testing.

Trilogy Education | Teaching Assistant - Software Development | Sept 2018 - Feb 2019

- Continuing Education Program for University of Washington providing students with one-on-one mentorship in debugging, problem solving, and time management.
- Bootcamp utilized MERN Full Stack (MongoDB, Express.js, React.js, Node.js) stacked module learning and Agile.

Design Imports | Product Manager | Sept 2017 – Nov 2017

- Designed ad campaigns on Amazon utilizing headline search, product display, sponsored ads, A+ content and hidden search terms to improve click-through rate and ROI.
- · Created and managed an online catalog of over 1000 products, including familial grouping of products.

Amazon | TAM - Kindle Content Operations | Jun 2016 - May 2017

- Created and adapted weekly and monthly metrics reports using SQL, leading expansion to global level (Multi-marketplace).
- · Identified and executed high impact projects leading to global performance improvements (TitleSet linking project).
- Worked across teams (VM, BI/BA and Publishers) to get content online.
- Created and updated SOP documents for above processes.

Amazon | TAM - Digital Video Games & Software | Oct 2014 – Sept 2015

- Worked as QA Liaison to run manual user and regression testing of the globally launched Developer Portal V2, tested, verified and tracked products passed the Amazon Quality Assurance criteria and rating system reducing bugs by 12%.
- Designed and edited product pages in HTML and CSS.

Amazon | Investigation Specialist – Fulfilled By Amazon | Aug 2013 – Jul 2014

- Used the internal Amazon trouble ticketing system to triage and resolved 4% inbound logistical issues between Sellers and Fulfillment Centers.
- · Identified fraudulent patterns and products within the pipeline to be quarantined and deep dived the root cause.
- Helped to redesign the training documents that decreased the on-boarding time from 4 weeks to 2 weeks.

Google Maps | Visual Data Specialist, Bothell WA, May 2012-Aug 2013

• Fixed user reported GIS (geographic information system) and directional issues regarding functionality of Google Maps

Education

Code Fellows, June 2018 | Certificate - Advanced Software Development in Full-Stack JavaScript University of Washington, Seattle, WA | Bachelor of Science - Physics